Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

# Sandip Kumar Pradhan (1) Featured



Have an overall IT experience around 4 years 9 month of Experience in Software Industry. Have an IT experience around 1 years 4 month in Data Science for Analytics and Machine Learning Use Case. Hands on experience in Python, pyspark, Numpy, Pandas



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer (Data Science)

Current Company: Cisco Systems

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Data Science, Data Mining, Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Cisco Unified

Communications, Agile Methodology, Service Delivery, Software

Engineering, Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, Github, Scikit learn, pyspark

Email - id Verified: Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Have an overall IT experience around 4 years 9 month of Experience in Software Industry.

Have an IT experience around 1 years 4 month in Data Science for Analytics and Machine Learning Use Case.

Hands on experience in Python, pyspark, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, MemSQL.

Hands on experience on Analytics, and very us machine learning technique like classification, regression, Clustering also working on Random Data and Time series Data.

Good exposure on Data preprocessing and data visualization, EDA also good Exposer on Text preprocessing and Messaging API using Kafka.

Working experience Data Validation using pydentic also deploying E2E flow in AWS Environment.

Having good experience in Agile Methodology and ability to handle independence Work.

Experience with developing Product oriented Application and also working on multiple POC for finalizing technology Also working Experience in UT and

Working on Deferent domain like Networking, Ecommerce, Health Care

# Work Experience

Cisco Systems as Senior Software Engineer (Data Science)

Aug 2019 to Till Date

Senior Software Engineer, Data Science seeking roles in Data Mining, Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Use Cases, Cisco Unified Communications, Agile Methodology, Service Delivery, Software Engineering, Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, GIT

**INNOMINDS** as Software Engineer (Developer)

Mar 2018 to Jul 2019

SMAK Solutions as Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2016 to Mar 2018

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2015

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Python, Numpy, Pandas, MySQL		
JIRA		
WINDOWS		
pycham, ipython Note Book		
GIT		
CICD		
Putty/putty Gen, SonalrLint		
MEMSQL	0	1 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Oriya	Expert			

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Authorized to Work in the US

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time